There are awesome packages for data analysis in Python.
هناك حزم رائعة لتحليل البيانات في Python.
A package is a collection of modules or python files that we can import into our code.
الحزمة هي مجموعة من الوحدات النمطية أو ملفات Python التي يمكننا استيرادها إلى الكود الخاص بنا.
You can think of them as libraries of useful classes and functions that we can use.
يمكنكم النظر إليها على أنها مكتبات للفئات والدوال المفيدة التي يمكننا استخدامها.
As a very simple example,
كمثال شديد البساطة،
let's say we wanted to find the mean of a list.
فلنقُل إننا أردنا أن نعثر على العدد المتوسط لقائمة ما.
We could code that manually by finding
يمكننا كتابة كود لذلك يدويًا، عن طريق
the sum and dividing that by the length of the list.
العثور على الملخص وقسمته على طول القائمة.
We could even create a function for it if we wanted to reuse it in multiple places.
يمكننا حتى أن ننشئ دالة له إذا أردنا أن نعيد استخدامه في مواضع متعددة،
Or, we could just get this function from a library like Numpy.
أو يمكننا الحصول على هذه الدالة ببساطة من مكتبة مثل Numpy.
Here, we are importing the package.
سنستورد الحزمة هنا.
This is typically done at the beginning of your file.
عادةً ما يتم ذلك في بداية الملف الخاص بكم.
NP is the conventional alias for Numpy.
NP هو الاسم المستعار التقليدي لـ Numpy.
Importing it without the alias is still valid but can quickly get annoying
يظل استيراده بدون الاسم المستعار أمرًا متاحًا؛ لكنه يمكن أن يصبح مزعجًا بسرعة
if you reference it a lot which will be the case for the packages we're using.
إذا أشرتم إليه كثيرًا؛ وهي الحالة التي ستكون عليها الحزم التي سنستخدمها.
Using a short alias helps keep your code concise and clean.
يساعد استخدام اسم مستعار قصير في إبقاء الكود الخاص بكم موجزًا ونظيفًا.
Three powerful packages for data analysis that
هناك ثلاث حزم قوية لتحليل البيانات
we'll be using are Numpy, Pandas and Matplotlib.
سوف نستخدمها، وهي Numpy وPandas وMatplotlib.
Numpy let's you perform mathematical functions on
يسمح لكم Numpy بأداء دوال رياضية
large multi dimensional arrays and matrices efficiently.
على مصفوفات كبيرة متعددة الأبعاد بشكل كفء.
Pandas is like a more powerful and flexible version
يبدو Pandas كنسخة أكثر قوة ومرونة
of Excel that can handle large amounts of data.
من Excel يمكنها معالجة كميات كبيرة من البيانات.
And, Matplotlib is a plotting library that can produce
وMatplotlib هو مكتبة لرسم المخططات يمكنها إنتاج
great visualizations often with very few lines of code.
مرئيات رائعة عادةً ما تتضمن سطورًا قليلة جدًا من الكود.
Links to documentation for these packages are provided in the instructor notes.
تجدون روابط للتوثيق لهذه الحزم متوفرة في ملاحظات المعلم.
Many people can be overwhelmed when they first try to navigate
قد يشعر الكثيرون بالإحباط حين يجرِّبون استكشاف
the docs to learn and master these packages, especially Pandas.
المستندات للمرة الأولى كي يتعلموا ويتمكَّنوا من هذه الحزم، لا سيما مع Pandas.
We'll slowly introduce tools from each one throughout this course so that you can
سنتعرَّف ببطء على أدوات من كل حزمة على مدار هذه الدورة التدريبية، حتى يمكنكم
be comfortable using them and confident learning new things on your own with the docs.
الشعور بالارتياح عند استخدامها والشعور بالثقة بينما تتعلمون بأنفسكم أشياء جديدة باستخدام المستندات.